<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human on Carl Gaspar</title>
    <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/tags/human/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Human on Carl Gaspar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://10.10.30.2:1313/tags/human/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DotA 2 - Reaching Divine Rank</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/dota-2-reaching-divine-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/dota-2-reaching-divine-rank/</guid>
      <description>I DID IT! Finally reached Divine rank (4600 mmr) in DotA 2! I just want to prove to myself that I understand the mechanics of the game and I&amp;rsquo;m still capable of solving problems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing this game on and off even before my age reached double digits.&#xA;First I tried to reach 3000 mmr (tiered rank does not exist yet at that time) from 2000 mmr then I stopped for 8 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My ACL Reconstruction Log</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/my-acl-reconstruction-log/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/my-acl-reconstruction-log/</guid>
      <description>Title Note Week/Day Date I am going for prehab to strengthen my muscles prior to operation. W-2 I am now doing all the exercises by myself everyday prior to operation. I followed this guy&amp;rsquo;s guide: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Czx6LUnG1cs W-1 Surgery day I was put to mild sleep, then after an hour, it&amp;rsquo;s done, good shit! I feel weird that everything is okay, I can do ankle pumps but not quad sets but nothing hurts, I was waiting in a room and feel like I can go out and pee by myself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Are the Factors for Nail Growth?</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/what-are-the-factors-for-nail-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/what-are-the-factors-for-nail-growth/</guid>
      <description>Question This question has popped to my head after looking at my todolist. It goes something like this:&#xA;💅 Cut the nails&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve set this task so that I have a reminder to cut them once they reach a specific length. This has become a problem because I play a lot of basketball and longer nails than usual means something will change in my shot. The chances of it going in will be smaller than usual (not skill issue btw).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Part of the Top 1.1% - How Valorant Helped Me Think Critically</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/being-part-of-the-top-1.1-percent-how-valorant-helped-me-think-critically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/being-part-of-the-top-1.1-percent-how-valorant-helped-me-think-critically/</guid>
      <description>First posted on: 2021-11-30T00:00:00+08:00&#xA;Introduction Valorant is a free-to play 5 versus 5 FPS (first-person tactical hero shooter) game developed and published by Riot Games on 2020. Simply put, it&amp;rsquo;s like CS:GO but with abilities.&#xA;I played this game because I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to play at that time, the system requirements is pretty low, and my computer can easily handle it. It is not my first FPS game but I can confidently say that it is the first FPS game that I seriously played.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top 8 Soft Skills</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/top-8-soft-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/top-8-soft-skills/</guid>
      <description>Leadership Skills Guide a group from A to B May not be connected to an official leadership position Communicate goals and vision Coach, teach, mentor, and motivator Facilitate, build consensus, and engage entire team Communication Skills Clear and concise updates at meetings Easy to follow emails and reports Good &amp;ldquo;Vibe&amp;rdquo;: eye contact, facial expression, body language, and tone Public speaking, storytelling, and persuasion Interpersonal Skills Listening well Positive attitude Friendly and courteous Rapport, empathy, and humor Assertive but not aggressive Diplomatic when disagreeing Giving and receiving criticism well Work Ethic and Self-Motivation Take responsibility Take initiative Show self-direction Meet deadline, attendance, and time management expectations Teamwork Collaborate and cooperate Connect well with members on the team and with other stakeholders Take a team-based, collectivistic view Contribute to discussions that are outside of personal area of expertise Problem Solving Find a way to move forward Use critical thinking and logical reasoning Make good, informed decisions Prepare and take systematic and resourceful approach Flexibility and Adaptability Be open to change Find new ways to do things Have good self-awareness Respond well to uncertainty Be open and trainable Work well under deadlines and pressure Conflict Management Don&amp;rsquo;t cause conflict Don&amp;rsquo;t create &amp;ldquo;drama&amp;rdquo; Avoid a win-lose philosophy Deal with conflict appropriately and productively Look for common ground and helpful solutions Use a win-win philosophy References What Are Soft Skills?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
