<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Game on Carl Gaspar</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/game/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Game on Carl Gaspar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DotA 2 - Reaching Divine Rank</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/dota-2-reaching-divine-rank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/dota-2-reaching-divine-rank/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I DID IT! Finally reached Divine rank (4600 mmr) in DotA 2! I just want to prove to myself that I understand the mechanics of the game and I&amp;rsquo;m still capable of solving problems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing this game on and off even before my age reached double digits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First I tried to reach 3000 mmr (tiered rank does not exist yet at that time) from 2000 mmr then I stopped for 8 years. Tried again to reach 4000 mmr and finally, I&amp;rsquo;m here!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Part of the Top 1.1% - How Valorant Helped Me Think Critically</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/being-part-of-the-top-1.1-percent-how-valorant-helped-me-think-critically/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/being-part-of-the-top-1.1-percent-how-valorant-helped-me-think-critically/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First posted on: 2021-11-30T00:00:00.000Z&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Valorant is a free-to play 5 versus 5 FPS (first-person tactical hero shooter) game developed and published by Riot Games on 2020. Simply put, it&amp;rsquo;s like CS:GO but with abilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I played this game because I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to play at that time, the system requirements is pretty low, and my computer can easily handle it. It is not my first FPS game but I can confidently say that it is the first FPS game that I seriously played.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s More Find in the Philippines</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/projects/it-s-more-find-in-the-philippines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/projects/it-s-more-find-in-the-philippines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.galore.imfitphilippines&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s More Find in the Philippines&lt;/a&gt; is a 2D android-based find the hidden object game. Over a hundred objects are hidden in the different regions of the Philippines. It features most of the known objects from every region which lets you explore the country as well as learn trivia provided by the game. It&amp;rsquo;s More find in the Philippines lets you explore the country. Users will be asked to look for precious objects related to certain places. Users will consume energy to play a level or a stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
