<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Write-Up on Carl Gaspar</title>
    <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/tags/write-up/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Write-Up on Carl Gaspar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://10.10.30.2:1313/tags/write-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top 8 Soft Skills</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/top-8-soft-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/posts/top-8-soft-skills/</guid>
      <description>Leadership Skills Guide a group from A to B May not be connected to an official leadership position Communicate goals and vision Coach, teach, mentor, and motivator Facilitate, build consensus, and engage entire team Communication Skills Clear and concise updates at meetings Easy to follow emails and reports Good &amp;ldquo;Vibe&amp;rdquo;: eye contact, facial expression, body language, and tone Public speaking, storytelling, and persuasion Interpersonal Skills Listening well Positive attitude Friendly and courteous Rapport, empathy, and humor Assertive but not aggressive Diplomatic when disagreeing Giving and receiving criticism well Work Ethic and Self-Motivation Take responsibility Take initiative Show self-direction Meet deadline, attendance, and time management expectations Teamwork Collaborate and cooperate Connect well with members on the team and with other stakeholders Take a team-based, collectivistic view Contribute to discussions that are outside of personal area of expertise Problem Solving Find a way to move forward Use critical thinking and logical reasoning Make good, informed decisions Prepare and take systematic and resourceful approach Flexibility and Adaptability Be open to change Find new ways to do things Have good self-awareness Respond well to uncertainty Be open and trainable Work well under deadlines and pressure Conflict Management Don&amp;rsquo;t cause conflict Don&amp;rsquo;t create &amp;ldquo;drama&amp;rdquo; Avoid a win-lose philosophy Deal with conflict appropriately and productively Look for common ground and helpful solutions Use a win-win philosophy References What Are Soft Skills?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Risk Management Framework</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/risk-management-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/risk-management-framework/</guid>
      <description>Standards for Risk Management NIST SP 800-30 Risk Management Guide for Information Technology Systems Provides a foundation for the development of an effective risk management program Contains the definitions and the practical guidance for assessing and mitigating risks Provides information on the selection of cost-effective security controls NIST SP 800-30: Risk Management At a high level, risk management encompasses three processes. &amp;gt; Evaluation and Assessment &amp;gt; Risk Assessment &amp;gt; Risk Mitigation &amp;gt; Risk Assessment Steps Abstracted from SP 800-30 Step 1: System Characterization Step 2: Threat Identification Step 3: Vulnerability Identification Step 4: Control Analysis Step 5: Likelihood Determination Step 6: Impact Analysis Step 7: Risk Determination Step 8: Control Recommendations Step 9: Results Documentation Step 1: System Characterization Input Hardware Software System Interfaces Data and Information (Need to categorize how sensitive are these data) People System Mission Output System Boundary System Functions System and Data Criticality System and Data Sensitivity Step 2: Threat Identification Input History of system attack Data from intelligence agencies, mass media, or gov CERT Output Threat Statement Step 3: Vulnerability Identification Input Reports from prior risk assessments Prior audits Security requirements Security test results Output List of potential vulnerabilities Step 4: Control Analysis Input Current controls Planned controls Output List of current and planned controls Step 5: Likelihood Determination Input Threat-source motivation Threat capacity Nature of vulnerability Current controls Output Likelihood rating Likelihood Rating Qualitative Ratings High - The threat-source is highly motivated and sufficiently capable, and controls to prevent the vulnerability from being exercised are ineffective.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Risk Management Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/cyber-risk-management-fundamentals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/cyber-risk-management-fundamentals/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals of Cyber Risk Management Course Introduction Course Agenda Risk Management Overview Risk Management Frameworks Critical Assets and Operations Threats and Vulnerabilities Risk Analysis and Mitigation Security Controls Mitigation Strategy Maintenance Response and Recovery Risk Management Overview NIST SP 800-30 Defines risk as “a measure of the extent to which an entity is threatened by a potential circumstance or event, and typically a function of: (i) the adverse impacts that would arise if the circumstance or event occurs; and (ii) the likelihood of occurrence” At a high level, this is accomplished by balancing exposure to risks against cost of mitigation and implementing appropriate countermeasures/controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Security Maturity Roadmap by Scott Piper</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/aws-security-maturity-roadmap-by-scott-piper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/aws-security-maturity-roadmap-by-scott-piper/</guid>
      <description>Most common security incidents Publicly accessible resources such as S3 buckets or ElasticSearch clusters. Leaked access keys. For example, access keys posted to GitHub. Compromised IAM Roles through SSRF or RCE against an EC2, resulting in access to the metadata service at 169.254.169.254. AWS Security Maturity Roadmap Stage 1: Inventory Identify all AWS accounts in the company and their points of contact. Integrate AWS accounts into AWS Organizations. Ensure all account root emails are on distribution lists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Team Adversary Emulation With Caldera Part 2</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/_draft-red-team-adversary-emulation-with-caldera-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/_draft-red-team-adversary-emulation-with-caldera-part-2/</guid>
      <description>how to use the Mitre ATT&amp;amp;CK.&#xA;Source: https://youtu.be/EIHLXWnK1Dw</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incident Response: Detection and Analysis</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/incident-response-detection-and-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/incident-response-detection-and-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Research The Domain DNS Dumpster Doing a research on the domain using DNS Dumpster will provide DNS Records, much like the same information you&amp;rsquo;ll get when you register a web server.&#xA;Shodan.io Used to identify externally exposed ports, web servers, and devices. Using this tool will give you the perspective of an attacker scanning an entity.&#xA;VirusTotal If an organization is compromised by an actor who is then leveraging that compromised infrastructure to attack other organizations, other organizations may have already reported that to virus total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incident Response: Detection and Analysis</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/zzz-incident-response-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/zzz-incident-response-tools/</guid>
      <description>Research The Domain DNS Dumpster Doing a research on the domain using DNS Dumpster will provide DNS Records, much like the same information you&amp;rsquo;ll get when you register a web server.&#xA;Shodan.io Used to identify externally exposed ports, web servers, and devices. Using this tool will give you the perspective of an attacker scanning an entity.&#xA;VirusTotal If an organization is compromised by an actor who is then leveraging that compromised infrastructure to attack other organizations, other organizations may have already reported that to virus total.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information Security Governance for CISM®</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/zzz-information-security-governance-for-cism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/zzz-information-security-governance-for-cism/</guid>
      <description>Enterprise Governance&#xA;Information Security Governance&#xA;Exam Topics&#xA;Organizational culture&#xA;Legal, regulatory, and contractual requirements&#xA;Organizational structure, roles, and responsibilities&#xA;GRC = Governance, Risk, Compliance&#xA;Key points&#xA;Governance is key to the establishment of accountability and direction&#xA;Governance should eb addressed from an enterprise-wide viewpoint&#xA;Information security strategy must be aligned with organizational mission and goals&#xA;Factors That Influence Governance Organizational Culture Organizational norms and behaviors Management style: Autocratic (Taylorism) - All decisions are made by managers and everyone who&amp;rsquo;s not a manager just does what their tool to do.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red Team Adversary Emulation With Caldera Part 1</title>
      <link>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/_draft-red-team-adversary-emulation-with-caldera-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://10.10.30.2:1313/security/_draft-red-team-adversary-emulation-with-caldera-part-1/</guid>
      <description>how to use the Mitre ATT&amp;amp;CK.&#xA;Source: https://youtu.be/EIHLXWnK1Dw</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
